In the previous video,
前のビデオでは
I showed you that the position of a jerk
躍度最小トラジェクトリーの位置は 5 次多項式
minimizing trajectory is given by a quintic polynomial.
によって得られることを示しました
In this video, I'm going to present a quick and non-rigorous
このビデオでは これらの多項式を表す 6 つの係数の
walk through of how we find the six coefficients that describe these polynomial.
見つけ方について簡単にお見せしようと思います
It is not essential that you remember the details of this,
この詳細を覚えることは必須ではありませんが
but you might find it interesting.
興味深いことがわかると思います
First, we differentiate the equations of
まず 速度の方程式を得るために
the position in order to get the equations for the velocity,
位置の方程式を微分します そして 加速度の方程式を
and then we differentiate it again in order to get the equation for the acceleration.
得るために再度それを微分します
Now, we could just plug in our six boundary conditions to get the six equations.
これで 6 つの境界条件を代入するだけで 6 つの方程式を得られます
But first we're going to do something that will make our life a little bit easier.
でも まずはもう少し簡単になるような作業をしましょう
We're going to set the initial time as zero and when we do that, we find this.
最初の時間を 0 に設定し それを行うと こうなります
Which means that three or four unknowns don't need to be identified anymore,
つまり 3 4 個の未知数をもう特定しなくてよくなり
which reduces the program from six unknowns to three.
プログラムで 6 つの未知数が 3 つに減ります
It simplifies those three trajectories by removing three of the unknowns here.
ここの 3 つの未知数がなくなり これら 3 つのトラジェクトリーが簡素化されます
We can gather the known terms into functions of
既知の項をスター境界条件の関数
the star boundary conditions to make it look like a bit cleaner.
にまとめて 少し見やすくできます
The C1, C2, and C3 terms are functions of the initial conditions.
C1 C2 C3 の項は初期条件の関数です
What remains is that we only have to identify three parameters,
あとは N 境界条件にのみ依存する
that depends only on our N boundary condition.
3 つのパラメーターを特定するだけです
Those equations look like this,
それらの方程式はこのようになり、
and we know the final position,
最終の位置、速度tfの時の加速度がわかります
velocity and acceleration at time tf since those are all the quantities that we beat.
これらは全て満足した量だからだです
Since we know them,
これらがわかったので
a more useful way to think of these equations is like this,
これらの方程式を考える便利な方法はこのようなものとなり
where I have deliberately separated
ここでは求めたい未知の変数から既知の量を
the known quantities from the unknown variables that we wish to determine.
意図的に分けています
This is starting to look like a very solvable system of three equations.
これで 非常に解きやすい 3 つの方程式のシステムのように見えてきました
The best way to solve this is with a matrix that looks like this,
これを解く最良の方法は このような行列で
and this problem can be solved by inverting this matrix
この問題は 行列数学ライブラリを使ってこの行列の逆行列を
using any matrix mathematical library, which we will do later.
求めることで解けます これは後ほど行います